Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of AFL-CIO Serials WAG.362
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of AFL-CIO Serials
1887-2001
1940-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Federation of Labor
Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.)
AFL-CIO
Illinois State Federation of Labor
Illinois State AFL-CIO
WAG.362
10.5 Linear Feet in 24 manuscript boxes and two flat boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of AFL-CIO Serials contains over 100 titles published by and about the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations. The collection dates between 1887 and 2001, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1940s through the 1980s. Topics include labor related convention proceedings, council and president reports, and United States politics.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to the AFL-CIO drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of AFL-CIO Serials contains over 100 titles published by and about the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO). The collection dates between 1887 and 2001, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1940s through the 1980s. Topics include state and national AFL, CIO, and AFL-CIO annual and constitutional convention proceedings; council and president reports; and AFL-CIO reports on United States politics. The majority of the publications are conference proceedings from national CIO and AFL-CIO conventions, as well as Illinois State Federation of Labor and the Illinois State Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations. Other organizations represented include the New York State AFL-CIO, Iowa State Federation of Labor, the AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education (COPE), and the AFL-CIO's Industrial Union Department.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of certain original materials, researchers may be required to consult microfilm copies, preservation photocopies, or digital images of material in this collection.
Related Materials
For more serials on labor organizations and labor-related topics, see the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Labor Movement Serials, WAG.345.
Labor unions -- United States -- Periodicals.; Central labor councils.; Labor and laboring classes -- United States.; Labor laws and legislation -- United States.; Labor movement -- United States.; Proceedings.; Official reports.; Labor unions -- Congresses.
- 10 Years of CIO Winter 1947-48 Report: Cleveland Industrial Union Council, Cleveland, OH (Box 25, Folder 1)
- 1945: An Epochal Year: American Federation of Labor, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A Message to American Labor: Delivered at the 3rd Constitutional Convention of the AFL-CIO: American Trade Union Council for Histadrut, New York, NY, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- A Short History of American Labor: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Action on Executive Council Resolutions: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- AFL News-Reporter: American Federation of Labor, Washington, DC, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- AFL-CIO Brewery News of Tampa: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations Organizing Committee, Tampa Budweiser Workers, Tampa, FL, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO Guide to Union Sponsored Schoarships, Awards, and Student Financial Aid: AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- AFL-CIO Platform Proposals Presented to the Democratic and Republican National Conventions: AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO Song Book: AFL-CIO Department of Education, Washington, DC, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- America Needs a Raise: AFL-CIO Department of Economic Research, Washington, DC, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Labor and World Affairs: AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Annual Report by President Philip Murray, 14th Constitutionial Convention: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- BCTD Clipsheet: Building Construction Trades Dept., Washington, DC, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Boletín Latino-Americano del CIO: Comite de Asuntos Latino-Americanos, New York, NY, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Changing Situation of Workers and Their Unions: AFL-CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work, Washington, DC, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- CIO 1935-1955: Industrial Democracy in Action: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC (Box 1, Folder 22)
- The CIO: What It Is and What It Does: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- The CIO and World Affairs: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- CIO Minutes Digest: Los Angeles CIO Council, Los Angeles, CA, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- The CIO News: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1944-1951 (Box 24, Folder 18-21)
- The CIO News, European Edition: CIO European Office, Paris, France, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Collective Bargaining in the Public Sector: AFL-CIO Maritime Trades Department, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Conference of Representatives of National and International Unions Affiliated with the American Federation of Labor: American Federation of Labor, Cincinnati, OH, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Conference of Representatives of National and International Unions, The American Federation of Labor on Provisions of the Taft-Hartley Act: American Federation of Labor, Washington, DC, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Connecticut AFL-CIO News: Connecticut State AFL-CIO, Hamden, CT, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Connecticut Vanguard: Connecticut State CIO Council, Waterbury, CT, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Convention Proceedings: Illinois State Federation of Labor, Peoria, IL, 1929-1958 (Box 13, Folder 3-6, Box 14, Folder 1-4, Box 15, Folder 1)
- Convention Proceedings: Illinois State Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Illinois, 1958-1976 (Box 15, Folder 2-3, Box 16, Folder 1-3, Box 17, Box 18, Folder 1-4)
- Coordinated Collective Barganing Quarterly: CBQ: Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- COPE Clip-Sheet: AFL-CIO COPE, Washington, DC, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- COPE Committee on Political Education Newsletter: Chicago Federation of Labor AFL-CIO, Chicago, IL, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- COPE Newsletter: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, NY, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Daily Proceedings of the Ninth Constitutional Convention of the Congress of Industrial Organizations: Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Davis-Bacon News Reports: Building-Construction Trades Dept., AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Detroit Labor News: Metropolitan Detroit AFL-CIO Council, Detroit, MI, 1974-1993 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Education at Work: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Department of Education and Research, Washington, DC, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Elections: 1946: CIO Political Action Committee, New York, NY (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Executive Council Report: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Freedom From Want: The Story of Ohio Unemployment Compensation: Ohio CIO Political Action Committee, Columbus, OH, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- George Meany: The Making of a Freedom Fighter: 85th Birthday Tribute to George Meany Committee, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Government By Minority: The Case for Federal and State Legislative Reapportionment: Congress of Industrial Organizations Department of Education and Research, Washington, DC, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Helping America: Unions in Community Service: AFL-CIO Department of Community Services, Washington, DC, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Housing & Credit Newsletter: AFL-CIO Department of Economic Research, Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- In the Public Service: AFL-CIO Public Employee Department, Washington, DC, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11, Box 24, Folder 10)
- Industrial Union Department Bulletin: AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department, Washington, DC, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Industrial Union Department Digest: AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Issues & Answers: News, Information and Trends in the Public Sector: Public Employee Department, AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- IUD Legislative Alert: AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department, Washington, DC, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- IUD Newsletter: AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department, Washington, DC, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Labor and Education in 1955: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Labor Looks at Congress: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1959-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20-22, Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Labor News: Texas AFL-CIO: Texas AFL-CIO, Austin, TX, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Labor Union: National Newspapers Corp., Dayton, OH, 1952 (Box Shared Tamiment 050, Folder 3)
- Labor World: Duluth AFL-CIO Central Labor Body Affiliated Unions, Duluth, MN, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Labor Year in Review: Los Angeles County Federation of Labor, AFL-CIO, Los Angeles, CA, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Labor-Management Forum: CIO California Industrial Union Council, Los Angeles, CA, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Legislative Bulletin: New York State AFL-CIO, Albany, NY, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Legislative News Bulletin: New Jersey CIO, Newark, NJ, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Legislative Report: Rhode Island AFL-CIO, RI, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- List of New York State AFL-CIO Affiliated Organizations with Averaged Membership and Number of Delegates, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Los Angeles Citizen: Los Angeles American Federation of Labor, Los Angeles, CA, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Massachusetts State CIO Industrial Union Council 1951 Year Book: Massachusetts State CIO, Boston, MA (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Michigan CIO News: Michigan State Industrial Union Council (CIO), Detroit, MI, 1951-1955 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Minutes of the Seventh Constitutional Convention of the Congress of Industrial Organizations: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Chicago, IL, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Monthly Legislative Report: Public Employee Department, AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Needed: A Constructive Foreign Trade Policy: AFL-CIO, Industrial Union Department, Washington, DC, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- New Jersey CIO News: New Jersey State CIO Council, Newark, NJ, 1957-1960 (Box 24, Folder 4-7)
- New York State AFL-CIO 1983-1984 Labor Voting Record: New York State AFL-CIO, New York (Box 3, Folder 13)
- New York State AFL-CIO 1995 Legislative Report: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, NY (Box 3, Folder 16)
- New York State AFL-CIO Action on Affiliate Resolutions: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- New York State AFL-CIO Action on Executive Council Resolutions: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- New York State AFL-CIO Community Services News: Department of Community Services, Albany, NY, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- New York State AFL-CIO News: New York State AFL-CIO, Albany, NY, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- New York State AFL-CIO Twenty-fourth Constitutional Convention Proceedings: New York State AFL-CIO, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- New York State AFL-CIO Unity: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, NY, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- New York State-CIO 1945 Annual: New York State CIO Council, New York, NY (Box 3, Folder 18)
- New York State CIO Bulletin: New York State CIO Council, New York, NY, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- New York State CIO Reporter: New York State CIO Council, New York, NY, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 13)
- New York Trade Union Directory: Greater New York CIO Council, New York, NY, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- News AFL-CIO: AFL-CIO Department of Information, Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- News from the AFL-CIO: AFL-CIO Public Relations Department, Washington, DC, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Official Proceedings of New York State AFL-CIO Constitutional Conventions: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, NY, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- The Organizers: AFL-CIO Organizing Institute, Washington, DC, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 21, Box 24, Folder 12)
- Organizing for Social Justice in the Workplace: Department of Organization and Field Services, AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
- Partial Reports of Resolutions Committee UAW-CIO 15th Constitutional Convention, 1952-1955 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO News-COPE Newsletter: Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, Harrisburg, PA, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The People's Lobby: An AFL-CIO Report on the 97th Congress: AFL-CIO, Department of Legislation, Washington, DC, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Political Action Committee: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Postwar Forum: American Federation of Labor, New York, NY, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Privatization Update: Public Employee Department, AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1993-1998 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Proceedings of the Constitutional Convention of the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1959-1981 (Box 21, Folder 9-10, Box 22, Folder 1-3)
- Proceedings of the Constitutional Convention of the Congress of Industrial Organizations: Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1938-1954 (Box 18, Folder 5, Box 19, Folder 1-5, Box 20, Folder 1-4, Box 21, Folder 1)
- Proceedings of the Constitutional Convention of the Industrial Union Department AFL-CIO: Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO, 1955-1973 (Box 22, Folder 7-9, Box 23, Folder 1-2)
- Proceedings of the Convention of the Iowa State Federation of Labor: Iowa State Federation of Labor, Iowa, 1938-1952 (Box 21, Folder 4-7)
- Proceedings of the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor in the Matter of Charges Filed by the Metal Trades Department Against the Congress of Industrial Organizations and National and International Unions Holding Membership Thereon: American Federation of Labor, Washington, DC, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Public Service Reporter: Federation of Public Employees, AFT AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Recreation Round Up: Recreation Department, UAW-CIO, Detroit, MI, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Report: Executive Board Illinois State Federation of Labor: Illinois State Federation of Labor, Springfield, IL, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Report of President Philip Murray to the Constitutional Convention of the Congress of Industrial Organizations: Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1944-1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Report of Proceedings of the Second Annual Session of the American Federation of Labor: Convention of the American Federation of Labor/Concord Co-operative Printing Co., New York, NY, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Report of the AFL-CIO Executive Council: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1957-1987 (Box 11, Folder 6-8, Box 12, Folder 1-4)
- Report of the Committee on Resolutions: Sixth Constitutional Convention of the Congress of Industrial Organizations: Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Report of the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor to the Annual Convention: AFL Executive Council, 1932-1955 (Box 10, Folder 12-14, Box 11, Folder 1-5)
- Report of the Proceedings of the Annual Convention of the American Federation of Labor: American Federation of Labor, Washington, DC, 1921-1955 (Box 4, Folder 9-11, Box 5, Folder 1-5, Box 6, Folder 1-4, Box 7, Box 8, Folder 1-3, Box 9, Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Report of the Resolutions Committee Submitted to the Constitutional Convention of the Congress of Industrial Organizations by the Committee on Resolutions: Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1946-1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Report to the CIO Constitutional Convention: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1950-1955 (Box 12, Folder 9, Box 13, Folder 1)
- Report to the Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO and Convention Resolutions: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Resolutions: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
- The Safety Link: The Safety & Health Newsletter of the New York State AFL-CIO: New York State AFL-CIO, Albany, NY, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Second Constitutional Convention: Indiana State AFL-CIO, Indianapolis, IN, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Songs for Labor: American Federation of Labor Department of Education, Washington, DC, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Statements Adopted by the AFL-CIO Executive Council: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Supplemental Report of AFL-CIO Executive Council on Ethical Practice Cases: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Supplemental Report of AFL-CIO Executive Council to the Third Constitutional Convention: AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Twenty-Third Constitutional Convention New York State AFL-CIO Program and Committees: New York State AFL-CIO, New York, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Union Label and Service Trades News: Union Label and Service Trades Department of the State of New York, New York, NY, 1946-1958 (Box 22, Folder 10, Box 23, Folder 3, Box 24, Folder 1-3)
- Union Label Directory: American Federation of Labor, Washington, DC, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Washington Lookout: AFL-CIO Maritime Committee, Washington, DC, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Washington Newsletter: CIO Maritime Committee, Washington, DC, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Weekly News Service: American Federation of Labor, Washington, DC, 1929-1943 (Box Shared Tamiment 050, Folder 4-8)
- Workforce Bulletin: New York State AFL-CIO, Albany, NY, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 9)